{
    "id": "6e74e6560f8143d9afa71463df0983a3",
    "title": "Conditional Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………. the glass, it will break.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "drop",
                "dropped",
                "had dropped"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you start now, you ………………………… there on time.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will be",
                "would be",
                "would have been"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If he ………………………….. more money, he will have to do more work.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "wants",
                "wanted",
                "had wanted"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………… him, please ask him to give me a call.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "meet",
                "met",
                "had met"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………….. hurry up, you will be late for school.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "don't",
                "didn't",
                "hadn't"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ………………………… a million dollars, I could buy that home.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "had had"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If it rained, my plants …………………………. happy.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will be",
                "would be",
                "would have been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ……………………………. the Prime Minister, I would ban the sale of liquor.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "were",
                "am",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If I …………………………. the signal, I would have stopped.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "see",
                "saw",
                "had seen"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had told me you were coming, I ……………………………… cooked something special.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will have",
                "would have",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If they ………………………………… him early, they could have saved him.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "found",
                "find",
                "had found"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If he had fallen into the river, he ………………………………..",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will drown",
                "would drown",
                "would have drowned"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}